# **Mark Ulicnik**

Houston, TX | (832) 283-4119 | markulicnik@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | markulicnik.com

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER AND IT SPECIALIST

## **SUMMARY**

Computer Science graduate with a passion for putting technology to work. With emerging technologies growing rapidly, it is important to think critically about applications, security, and scalability of our systems with expanding context and capabilities. Passionate about growing clientele and utilizing expertise to meet their needs in any environment, whether through software, pool service, help desk support, or sales.

**TECHNICAL SKILLS** 

**Programming:** Python, C++, Javascript, SQL **Database:** Postgres, MySQL, MongoDB

**Certifications:** The Complete 2024 Web Development Bootcamp (Udemy) by TheAppBrewery **Software:** Microsoft (MS) Office Suite (Word, PowerPoint, Excel), Atlassian Confluence, Jira.

Visual Studio Code, NetBeans

**PROJECT EXPERIENCE** 

Personal Project, Houston, TX JULY 2024 – CURRENT

## Solo Developer | Digital Art Sharing Platform | React.js, PostgreSQL, Express.js, Node.js, HTML/CSS

Designing platform for digital artists to share and exchange artwork online

• Planned feature to implement "bounty board" where artists can submit art for competitions for cash prizes

Expected to be able to support ~50 users, and scale using Netlify hosting platform

College of Sciences & Technology Dept. — UHD, Houston, TX JANUARY 2024 – MAY 2024

# Sole Researcher | Logical Al Agents for Supply Chain Resilience | Automated Multiagent Planning

- Researched formalization and modeling technique for logical agents to improve supply chain
- Implemented logic programs to create system capable of answering user queries about resilience
- Developed knowledge of knowledge representation and logical reasoning for logical Al agents
- Presented research at 2024 Capitol of Texas Undergraduate Research Conference at UT Austin and 2024 UHD SRC hosted by the Scholar's Academy

College of Sciences & Technology Dept. — UHD, Houston, TX MAY 2023 - AUGUST 2023

## Student Project | Parkinson's Disease Detection using ML Classification Models | Python

- Trained 3 machine learning models to classify patients using features based on audio data
- Models were able to classify patients with a 93% accuracy measure
- Evaluated model based on accuracy, recall, F-1 score, and MCC to determine ability

## **RELEVANT EXPERIENCE**

PC Technician II | Lonestar College, Tomball OTS — Tomball, TX APRIL 2023 – CURRENT

- Supplied support for all Windows and Apple computers campuswide, phones, printers, and scanners
- Researched and delivered solutions to user requests amongst regular duties each day
- Followed talks from LSC System leadership, discussing developments in industry standards and updates in best practices for IT service

Research Assistant | CSET Dept. UHD, Houston, TX

NOVEMBER 2023 - MAY 2024

- Studied how to acquire and process data to train machine learning models for classification
- Utilized anomaly detection and machine learning algorithms to classify RNA data for chromatin loop bindings
- Reported research findings in weekly meetings to communicate changes to performance metrics

## **EDUCATION**

B.S.: Computer Science | University of Houston-Downtown (UHD), Houston, TX MAY 2024

**GPA:** 3.8

Awards: Dean's List (3 out of 3 semesters)

Memberships: UHD Association of Computing Machinery (ACM), Computing Alliance of Hispanic Serving

Institutions (CAHSI)

Relevant Courses: Data Structures and Algorithms, Software Engineering, Natural Language Processing, Database

Management Systems, Statistical & Machine Learning, Web Programming, Artificial Intelligence

A.S.: Computer Science | Lonestar College System, Cypress, TX DECEMBER 2022

(References Available upon Request)